Alex Loughlin

Front-End Web Developer

London

I am a front-end web developer with a keen eye for design and thoughtful UI and UX. I enjoy the unique role front-end web work has in solving usability problems and achieving clients desired aims for their sites. I feel that good front-end development is the key differentiating point between successful and unsuccessful websites.

My most recent work has focused on large-scale event websites, many of which rely directly on successful sites to drive new business to a rapidly growing company. Most of this work has been incorporating custom Wordpress solutions and a lesser known CMS called Affino. In the past, I have worked with smaller e-commerce sites to implement brand new websites and cms using Shopify. I also have a keen desire to drive more work towards static site generators such as Jekyll and for larger projects to implement React.

I personally love the challenge of designing beautiful and easy to use UIs. Then taking those designs and translating them into great products. I am looking forward to working with a team of people who are also enthusiastic about tackling the main varied and new problems facing web and application design.

To see examples of my work please visit my personal website at www.alexloughlin.com

Work Experience

Govnet Communications

Front-End Web Developer | Jan, 2017 - Current

My role at Govnet has been an interesting and varied one as I have been working on a very small four-person in-house team. Even though it is a small team, we are responsible for over 40 event sites including expos which have an attendance of nearly 5000 people. This scale means we have to liaise with 6 different divisions split across the company all with separate and competing events and timescales. We must take every project from starting concept to finished website ourselves, without the aid of a project manager,

juggling our time, workload and the client's expectations. As the Govnet's graphic designers are focused on print work (event signage), most of the initial designs and layouts for sites comes from us. Thus I have to take on much more of a design role and are never simply just given wireframes to build.

Every event site is a custom Wordpress build, never using any off the shelf themes. This allows us the complete flexibility to build interesting and effective elements for every show. From specific Agenda layouts to custom payment gateways. This custom approach does not mean that our development and turnaround times are slow. In the case of the Public Sector Show, this entire site was designed and built from scratch in three weeks, with the new site seeing every positive metric increasing compared to the old one.

Recently we have begun the large task of implementing a brand new CMS and CRM system for the entire company portfolio called Affino. The Affino platform gives us much more scope to centralise our websites and all the customer info the company holds. This has been a massive undertaking, involving building brand new sites in a new system, restructuring all data and teaching content managers how to use a new system.

- The Public Sector Show https://psshow.co.uk
- UK Health Show https://ukhealthshow.com/
- Blockchain Live https://blockchainlive.com/
- Fraud & Error https://fraudanderror.co.uk/

Vitamin London

Junior Front End Developer | Jul, 2016 - Dec, 2016

My time at Vitamin London was spent mainly being the sole front-end developer on a variety of projects. These projects were mostly e-commerce sites using Shopify and some Wordpress based projects. One example project is Van Loon Sport, a new and high-end ski-wear brand based out of London. Their website, vanloonsport.com, uses Shopify and a basic theme. I was responsible for the main functionality and set up of the website, making sure the structure and user journey matched the Client's exacting expectations.

As Vitamin London is a small design agency, I was given many chances to interact very closely with clients. Making sure their projects got to the exact place the Client envisioned them.

Education

University of Westminster

First Class Honours - Multimedia Computing (BSc) | Sep, 2013 - Jun, 2016

My university degree allowed my to try a wide and varied range of topics from the computer science world. During my three years I was exposed to everything from Java and Unix, web design to animation and even cyber security. This allowed me learn which elements of the industry I really enjoyed. So that when it came to my third year I was able to specialise. My specific interests ended up being Responsive Web Design and Mobile Design (Web and native applications). I enjoyed the challenge of designing and testing well thought out user interfaces and experiences. Then bringing them to life through programming languages such as Swift, HTML5 and Javascript specifically.

Projects

Before You Eat - iOS App

Designer and Developer | Dec, 2015 - Jun, 2016

Before You Eat is a mobile application, which will teach users how to alter their relationship to food. Before You Eat was built using Swift to run specifically on Apple iPhones. Over the course of this project, I have developed a deep understanding of the Swift language and designing for iOS platforms specifically. As during this project I took it from conception, through to design and then implementation and testing.

The application features interactive lessons which will guide the user on their journey to see why fad dieting will never work for them and how to think differently about food. Before You Eat will show you that there is more to dieting than counting calories or just more exercise. It is about your relationship with food and how you change that.

Skills

CSS (including preprocessors such as SASS)

Javascript (jQuery and Vanilla)

Static Site Genorators - Jekyll

PHP

Responsive Design for Web

Swift

Grid based systems for scalable Web Design

Adobe CC Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop + Indesign)

Content Management Systems (Wordpress + Affino + Shopify)

Bootstrap

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email: aloughlin711@gmail.com

Telephone: 447590814386

Website: http://alexloughlin.com